that describe the same entity spread across multiple tables, data models with a structure that 
Database
Like column names, table names are part of both the data model and the data set’s vocabulary, 
Transformation patterns at the table level look for data issues in a single table, such as ambig-
•	 Invalid values that can be determined by inter-table rules.
19.  (LO 7)  Hamza is transferring data into an analytical database for analysis. Which steps should he 
•	 Four Table Transformation Patterns
ILLUSTRATION 5.36  Duplicate Service Table
The table is a sample of Stufan’s product data. Identify three quality issues with the data.
contains employee performance information. These are the data dictionaries for both tables.
as orders, sales, purchases, and payments. The fact table in the center of Illustration 5.5 
Demographics table does not have a primary key and there are matching issues between the 
Service table is the fact table, the Employee table is a who dimension, and the Client table is 
•	Renaming columns and tables.
Delete Redundant and Dependent Columns
Create and apply intra-table validation rules.
gradually at the column level, table level, and model level. This section focuses on trans-
This pattern focuses on primary keys. Tables are descriptions of entities, and each instance of 
b.	 Compared to fact tables, dimension tables typically have fewer instances and more columns.
 Columns that are not single-valued make analytics difficult. 
ing the values in the source data, or correcting the values in the analytical database.
While the number of columns in a fact table is generally small, they usually have many 
Visually scan tables for incorrect or ambiguous 
department. A sample of the list and the table’s data dictionary follows. 
•	 Invalid values that can be determined by intra-table rules.
Replace one value with another in the selected columns.
null values. Also, the Rate column in the Employee table cannot contain any null values 
Manage    Columns
The best method to detect composite or multi-valued columns is visual scanning. Examining 
Every table needs at least one column–or combination of columns–that meet the two 
how to instruct Power Query not to load a table. Right-click on EmployeeDemographics 
Let’s profile the ActualTime column in the Service table. Illustration 5.23 (A) displays 
Rename Columns
Access database
BE 5.3  (LO 1)  You have been provided with a data table that contains customer data collected for a retail 
•	 Columns that contain irrelevant and unreliable data.
All data recorded thus far is given to you in a CSV file. The data are also shown here. Notice that currently, 
column name accurately reflects its content. Here are four rules for naming columns:
Next, determine the row count for the Service table in the ETL tool used for extraction. Illus-
Recall from earlier in the chapter that combining two tables with a similar structure is called a 
Ambiguous Table Names
•	Apply: Apply all the transformations to the analytical database, but keep Power Query open.
CSV files and a PDF file with the data dictionaries for each. Apply the appropriate data preparation pa
Quality-oriented table patterns address:
ceptable value is assigned.
Apply patterns to transform columns.
Columns are not 
•	Build a frequency table, or a table that counts how many times a value occurs. Values with 
•	Splitting and combining tables.
a.	 There is no overlap between the columns.
	 d.	 The columns do not have the correct data type.
From Text/CSV
requires creating a new table. But because the employee data needs additional work, it makes 
1.	 The State column in the Customer table contains the value DN, which might be incorrect, 
 Patterns 10, 14, and 17 are similar because they define the acceptable values for a column. 
the values in either the source data or the analytical database. When modifying the values, 
Across Columns
intuitive, and unambiguous make it easier for other people to use a database and explore data. 
a sample of employee information. The data dictionary for the Driver table follows.
Columns?
Illustration 5.33 shows the structure of the combined table, which is named Employee.
STEP 7: Only the Employee table is needed for analytical purposes. Illustration 5.60 shows 
Dimensional modeling is the technique of creating data models with fact tables surrounded by 
of all their assets. The data dictionary for the asset table looks as follows:
Employee table: 
criteria discussed earlier. Columns that meet both criteria are candidate keys, and ETL 
Manage Columns
Transformation patterns at the model level search for data issues across tables, such as data 
tions, such as pie charts. However, poorly named columns make it complicated to develop 
ILLUSTRATION 5.58  Merge Tables with Fuzzy Matching
IBM Db2 database
them with the FirstName and LastName columns in the E-Dem table.
Merged Table
transform columns.
and sells them worldwide. The table provides a small sample of the customer information they track. They 
column in the analytical database. 
•	 Combining tables with a similar structure with a union. Com-
important because other people might use the analytical database. Essentially, column names 
of tables.
 ILLUSTRATION 5.39  Design and Implementation of an Inter-Table Validation Rule 
dimension tables. These data models, such as star schemas, are easy to understand and result 
IBM Informix database (Beta)
2.	 Label each table as fact or dimension and label each dimension table as who, when, or what.
vendor field into the Purchase table, or the other way around), Microsoft Access provides 
From Database 
d.	 Dimension tables are used for what, when, and who analysis.
transform tables.
table structures are preferred over crosstabulation tables
Split composite columns.
c.	 To make slicing data easier, most measures are defined as part of the dimension tables.
ical database.
more other columns in the same table.
Select a table and matching columns to create a merged table.
A column in the fixed assets table has a column for date acquired 
e.	 The grain represents the granularity level of a fact table.
Like Pattern 1, the row count for the analytical database can be compared with the row count 
	 1.	 Remove duplicate customer entries (Hint: There are 11 records in the original table; the clean table 
database, but not in the source data.
the order in which they are applied will depend on each project.  The other columns in the 
	 e.	 Only one employee is accountable for a payment.
tables in your analytical database. For each of the following four relationship specifications, identify the 
This information is available for all columns in Power Query. The illustration shows that 
CustomerCode field in the Customer table and the Customer field in the Sale table.
Multi-Valued Columns
to the Beans case. It is part of the Service table, and it specifies that only managers, sr. man-
in the Excel worksheet (Illustration 5.14) with the same number for the Service table in the 
would create a primary key for this table.
List the table transformation patterns (patterns 11–14) that are relevant for this data set and explain how 
For both the Service and Task tables, keep only the columns that are shown in Illustration 5.35.
EX 5.5  (LO 6)  Data   Auditing   Combine Tables and Identify Invalid Data Assume you are a 
ETL tools make it easy to extract data from databases, spreadsheets, text files, and many other 
The following two illustrations show the current relationship between the Sale and Customer tables 
5.5  Which Patterns Transform Tables?  5-33
To: Table (Column)
•	Adding and deleting columns.
Create and apply inter-table validation rules.
table follows. 
Combine Tables for Analysis
•	 Inconsistent data in columns. 
Identify tables missing a 
 Create a separate table for multi-valued columns. 
tableside point-of-sale (POS) systems on each of their 20 tables. They provide you the data for the first 
ues are and are not acceptable and they can take many shapes and forms. For example, an order 
ing two tables with different characteristics for the same entity is a merge or a join. The table 
ues. Each row in the table represents an invoice line. The first two rows in the table represent 
a.	 Review the columns for appropriate naming conventions.
Fact Table
Scan columns for incorrect or ambiguous names.
table cannot have the same name, Power Query automatically changed the second ID column in 
	 4.	 Transform the CustInfo column into two single-valued columns. Label one column Name and the 
users. An analytical database is the integrated data set used for analysis purposes. Unambig-
sis. Data loading is the process of making the analytical database available for use. Since both 
the Service table and click Load (Illustration 5.50).
Create and apply inter-table 
2.	 A 1-N cardinality pattern is expected for a relationship between a dimension table (customer) 
•	Transposing and unpivoting tables.
vendor–the vendor with ID 6–to the Purchase table. Access generates an error preventing you 
union. In Illustration 5.32, the table in panel (C) combines the two tables in panel (A). Combin-
Table
Fact Tables 
the transformations are applied to the analytical database. 
Table B
or more other tables. An example of a widely used inter-table validation rule is  referential 
1.	 The Sales table has a column with ambiguous heading-SP.
13.  (LO 5)  Which of the following statements is true about establishing a primary key in a table?
Review each table and identify three data matching challenges.
•	 A product’s category is determined by its table name and cannot be used for analysis pur-
d.	 Spokesperson represents an aggregate column, whereas Name and Sport represent sliced columns.
Creating a separate table for Certifications, results in a snowflake schema. In a snow-
1.	 The data in the LoyaltyRating column in the Customer table are not useful for analytical 
the name accurately reflects its content. The rules for naming tables are the same as those 
Redundant content among columns in a table 
Table as the value. Next, Click the right upper corner of the column: 
how to transfer data from the ETL tool, in this case Power Query, to the analytical database.
•	The CertificationList column in the E-Dem table is multi-valued.
3.	 Put the fact table in the center.
•	Duplicate the Employee table and name the duplication “Certifications.” 
Rename Tables
Remove columns with 
Tables?
Identify Similarly Structured Tables/Tables Describing Different 
•	 The three tables cannot be combined using a union since the table structure for the Dwarfs 
tables to validate inter-table rules for referential integrity. Which of the following is true about referential 
bining tables tables with different characteristics for the same 
•	 Columns with invalid data.
(B) Customer Table:
the Service table to ID-1 when loading the data.
Duplicate the Service table and rename the duplication “Task” (Illustration 5.36). 
with Intra-Table Rules
At this point, you have successfully merged the two tables into one.
•	 For example, it is common for data scientists to use table names such as DCustomer and 
table has now been split into two tables. Service is a fact table, and Task is a dimension table. 
Some information for the product with ID 1 is in the ProductDescriptions table. Other 
more specifically, additive. The values in these columns can be easily aggregated, or grouped 
10 COLUMNS, 999+ ROWS       Column profiling based on top 1000 rows
Visually scan columns for 
•	 Tables without a primary key.
Unpivot Only Selected Columns
Implementation of Intra-Table 
d.	 If a table does not have a primary key, it cannot be included in an analytical database.
Create a separate table for 
	 2.	 In panel (B) the two tables describe different characteristics of the same entity–Product. 
Loading moves the data from the ETL tool to the analytical database. Illustration 5.40 shows 
 ILLUSTRATION 5.47 Select and Load the Service Table
dation rules, including the following inter-table validation rule:
During data exploration and interpretation, column names in tables become variables. We 
Rename tables.
shows some potential name changes for columns. Note that, because two columns in the same 
12.  (LO 5)  Discuss the importance of minimizing redundant data among columns in an analytical 
 It would help if you could combine the information in both tables to automatically calculate the sales tax
designated with a number in the following table, identify the appropriate sentence or term to create the 
Data spread across tables. Identify tables with a similiar 
Scan for Composite and Multi-Valued Columns
4.	 Complete the star schema by connecting the tables and defining their cardinalities.
such as a customer’s email address. Here are two scenarios where two or more columns in a 
structure or tables that describe 
Invalid data might have been entered into one of the tables in 
such as Age, and then select Remove Columns. For the Beans data set, the irrelevant column, 
table transforms it into a single-valued column. Illustration 5.35 shows the data model we 
for naming columns. They should be intuitive, avoid spaces, underscores, and special coding:
•	 Combined or multi-valued columns.
•	Linking two tables by defining a relationship between them. Relationships are created 
table’s row count in the ETL tool. Illustration 5.14 shows the Service Excel worksheet. When 
•	Avoid special coding like DCustomer (the D refers to a dimension table, but not everyone 
Combine Tables for 
To correct the issue, delete the columns with irrelevant and unreliable data from the analyt-
columns. Data that do not meet these expectations are considered invalid.
BE 5.6  (LO 3)  Tax Accounting   You have been asked to develop an analytical database to analyze local 
Use the table transformation patterns to identify two data issues in the PTS file. 
and a fact table (sale). Customers can make more than one sale, but only one customer is spec-
The rate of Beans’ employees is determined by their job position. The table shows the minimum 
 Inter-table validation rules identify invalid data. Their creation requires in-depth knowledge 
An analytical database consists of an integrated set of tables, which is a data model, 
Columns
•	Splitting and merging columns.
1.	 Draw the different tables and their fields.
combined two ways. A union combines different tables with the same data structure. The 
Across Tables
databases are often posted in the cloud where they can be used simultaneously by many users. 
Between Tables
Dimension Tables
the ID field in the Vendor table and the Vendor field in the Purchase table. 
Select tables and columns that are related.
company’s customer loyalty program. An excerpt of that data table follows. Identify at least three data 
c.	 Primary keys and foreign keys are identical information repeated in the same table.
From: Table (Column)
The Task table should now mirror the one shown in Illustration 5.37. 
Single-Valued Columns 
columns. 
15.  (LO 5)  Consider a scenario where the following validation rule was applied to the Employee table 
multi-valued columns.
tables share the same primary key, a join, or merge, is straightforward. But the Employee­
ILLUSTRATION 5.37  Task Dimension Table
and federal sales tax compared to value-added tax. An excerpt of your data table is presented.
EX 5.3  (LO 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 7)  Data   Financial Accounting   Extraction, Column and Table Trans-
in panel (D) combines the two tables in panel (B). For the Beans case, both the Employee and 
	 2.	 Apply data preparation pattern 12. Does the table have a primary key? If not, describe how you 
	 1.	 Apply the principles of dimensional modeling to the Sales table by creating a star or snowflake 
ID column in the Service table. Similar tests can be run for the other columns.
d.	 Compare the row count for the analytical database with the row count of the data set in the ETL tool.
•	1: For every fact, there is just one corresponding value in each dimension table. For each 
3.	 Remove the LoyaltyRating column from the analytical database.
result is a table with more rows. Recall from the foundational data analysis chapter that a 
lytical database using one or more sources of raw data. 
Table transformation patterns deal with data problems in a single 
with Inter-Table Rules
columns contains both customer name data and payment term data.
Employee table. This information is useful in many ways:
Data loading is the process of making the analytical database available for use. Analytical 
c.	 create a separate table.
table names that is easy to understand and work with.
ILLUSTRATION 5.60  Select Tables that Should Not be Loaded
the Service table, and we opted not to specify a separate when dimension. However, TaskId, 
Identify Tables with a Primary Key Missing
 Split combined columns. 
	 b.	 All columns are not single-valued.
•	 As shown in Illustration 5.61, the relationship between the two tables is defined between 
5.4  Which Patterns Transform Columns?  5-25
and keep the CertificationList and University columns. 
in the Employee table now pays off!
or change the value in the analytical database. In the Beans data set, no invalid data were 
Crosstabulation tables have limitations for analysis. The names in the panel (A) column head-
In the resulting table, delete the Attribute column and change the Value column’s 
d.	 move the column to another table. 
table with more columns. 
FSales with D and F referring to certain types of tables. However, such terms might be confus-
ILLUSTRATION 5.38 Unpivoting Columns
	 1.	 Apply data preparation Pattern 11. The table is titled Amounts & Discounts. Propose a table name 
•	Combining two or more tables unites information about the same entity. Tables can be 
Visually scan the table for 
analytical database that shows the consolidated fixed assets for your entity. This analytical database 
Unpivot Other Columns
STEP 2: Select the Employee table in the Queries pane. Next, select the Home tab in Power 
Delete the duplicate rows in the Task table by selecting the Home tab in Power 
SQL Server database
the values of another column in the same table. Assume both age and date of birth are 
•	 Tables with two or more columns with overlapping content.
together, as measures. These measures can then be sliced using the columns in the next type 
 ILLUSTRATION 5.50 Select and Load the Service Table
Unpivot Columns
Transform Tables with 
•	Finally, select Unpivot Columns in the ribbon, and choose Unpivot other Columns 
table might have the same content:
Merge Columns
From Table/Range
Use the same process as before to create the CertificationList table:
the Service table and click Load (Illustration 5.47).
Barnes received a table of data from the IT group. One of the 
2.	 Use Data Exploration Pattern 11: Non-Intuitive and Ambiguous Table Names.
•	 Columns with incorrect data. 
Scan Columns for Irrelevant and Unreliable Data
STEP 4: Choose FirstName and LastName in both tables. Using Pattern 6 to split the name 
	 1.	 In panel (A) both tables, JanuarySales and FebruarySales, have the same structure but 
contains sales data. Data in a fact table are captured at a high granularity level to avoid 
correspond to business transactions. Dimension tables, on the other hand, describe who 
Create and Apply Intra-Table Validation Rules
Create and apply intra-table 
(C) Merged Customer Table
table. Structure-oriented table patterns address:
table names.
Some tables do not have a primary key.
Table A
each product category. She asks if there would be issues combining the three tables for analysis. How 
5.4  Which Patterns Transform Columns?  5-27
Domain-specific rules that determine whether data are acceptable can be created for most 
to remove rows from a table?  Illustration 5.9 shows that Power Query, Excel’s and Power 
•	 Power Query will let you select any column from the EmployeeDemographics table 
ILLUSTRATION 5.4  Crosstabulation Table Structure vs. Flat Table Structure
14.  (LO 5)  You are examining the columns in a data set that you are analyzing. The following columns 
❺  Apply patterns to transform tables.
Remove the columns or 
5.5  Which Patterns Transform Tables?  5-29
of the business.  Illustration 5.39 shows an example of an inter-table validation rule applied
Combined Employee Table
Scan Tables for Incorrect or Ambiguous Names
1.	 The current name of the worksheet/table is ambiguous. PTS stands for PurchaseTransactions, 
Most data analytics projects involve multiple tables, often from different data sources, which 
BE 5.4  (LO 2)  The following two tables must be integrated into one combined table. The combined table 
Union or merge tables. 
and state are listed in separate columns. In some cases, the state column displays the state name, 
Examining a table’s content and its data dictionary definition can help determine whether 
Relationships, the final element of data models, link tables and are rep-
table is different from the table structures of the Aristocats and Tintin tables. The QOH 
Power BI and Tableau are examples of data warehouses.
STEP 1: The Microsoft Access database contains the Vendor and Purchase tables: 
Stufan CEO Shanice suggests organizing product data in three separate tables, with one table for 
Union or merge tables.
Flat tables  5-6 
Creating a shared vocabulary requires identifying who is going to use the analytical database 
Examine the values in the columns. 
•	Close and apply: Close Power Query and apply all transformations to the analytical database.
Table Structures That Make Analysis Easier
and unclick the checkbox before Enable Load. Tables that are not loaded into the analytical 
•	 Columns with incomplete data.
tial number assigned to each row in the Sale table. As a result, the wrong customers are 
different rows. It is the sales table shown in panel (C) split horizontally. Questions about 
and EmployeeDemographics are such tables. The goal is to create a single table with all the 
Apply patterns to transform tables.
1.	 The table currently does not have a primary key, and none of the columns contain unique val-
poses. A Category column needs to be added to each of the three tables.
multiple tables. Illustration 5.32 shows two possible scenarios.
single table (named Sales) in a relational database. The data dictionary is given here.
	 2.	 Address these issues by transforming the table. 
•	In the new Certifications table, keep only the EmployeeID and the CertificationsList 
5.4  Which Patterns Transform Columns?  5-19
While the number of rows in a dimension table is usually small, they often have many 
Keep in mind that excluding data from an analytical database is not the same as deleting the 
and ensuring all fields belong to the correct table. In an accounting context, fact tables 
ILLUSTRATION 5.32  Combining Tables
PostgreSQL database
Irrelevant columns can be identified primarily by scanning the data visually. The data dictio-
database.
a.	 Primary keys must use the same column title in all related tables.
Transform Tables 
flake schema, the information for a dimension is spread across multiple tables. The schema 
a.	 Fact tables represent business transactions.
Incorrect or ambiguous table names make it 
First, create a Task Dimension table that captures the descriptions for services. 
with intra-table rules.
	 1.	 Describe the table’s data problems. 
	 a.	 Dimension tables
16.  (LO 6)  Discuss the benefits of single-valued columns and flat tables for slicing data. 
to the analytical database.
­Illustration 5.41 shows the finalized data model for the Beans analytical database created 
and add it to the Employee table. Uncheck the FirstName and LastName columns 
In practice, customer dimension tables often have more than 100 columns.
•	 Non-intuitive and ambiguous table names.
MySQL database
Rename columns.
A 1-N cardinality pattern for a relationship between a dimension and a fact table can be inter-
The EmployeeDemographics table does not have a candidate key. We could combine the first 
modeling principles when building an analytical database.
total sales amounts are easier to answer if all data are in one table.
shows, a star schema consists of two types of tables, fact tables and dimension tables, and the 
Illustration 5.44 shows the revised data dictionary for the analytical database in Illus-
Text/CSV
Visually scan columns for irrelevant and unreliable data. 
ations. Would you prefer the table in panel (A) or the table in panel (B) to answer a question 
with a substantial markup. You have been asked to create an analytical database to understand purchases 
sporting spokespersons for the company. Use the table to identify which of the following statements is true:
Illustration 5.16 (A), the Age column in the E-Dem table mixes null values, numbers, dates, 
To correct this issue, rename the table with an ETL tool, as name changes are automatically 
Be sure to retain the TaskID field in the Service table and to rename it “Task.” The Service 
•	The Name column in the Employee table mixes an employee’s first and last names. While 
one table ( Data See How To 5.2 to learn how to merge these tables with Power Query.).
STEP 3: Select the EmployeeDemographics table to join it with the Employee table.
The priority is to integrate their data into an analytical database. They hire your firm to help them. 
with inter-table rules.
 On the other hand, the CertificationList column’s multi-valued nature in the E-Dem table 
tified, add the missing rows to the analytical database.
and each table has several columns. This means that transformations can be conducted 
9.  (LO 4)  Lizelle is a financial analyst preparing an analytical database to analyze manufacturing data 
Related Table/Query:
database are shown in italics. Note: This option is available in power BI only, not in Excel
the database.
•	Close: Close Power Query without applying any transformations to the analytical database.
Use these dimensional modeling principles by determining the fact and dimension tables 
 Remove columns with irrelevant or unreliable data. 
 Create and Apply Inter-Table Validation Rules
Illustration 5.4 (A) shows a crosstabulation table representing a relationship between 
datasets
information for the same product, ID = 1, is in the ProductAccounting table. In this case, 
Illustration 5.34 structures the current analytical database as a star schema. The 
Merge Tables With Power Query
join, or merge, combines data elements or columns from different tables. The result is a 
Another best practice for structuring data is using flat tables, in which col-
You cannot add or change a record because a related record is required in table ‘VENDOR'.
Remove Columns With Irrelevant or Unreliable Data
A table with vendor information is named VINFO.
Identify tables missing a primary key.
d.	 Put the relevant, irrelevant, reliable, and unreliable data in separate columns.
culated as part of the analytical database. 
instance of the Sale table (an invoice line), there is one date, product, customer, and 
Columns that contain redundant information can be deleted. When there is dependency, 
	 b.	 Fact table
SQL Server Analysis Services database
fore, a new dimension table named Task can be created. Further, recall from Pattern 6 that 
•	Remove the CertificationList column from the Employee table. 
single-valued columns and flat tables.
❹  Apply patterns to transform columns.
Oracle database
Rename tables. 
become part of the database’s vocabulary. Recall that Beans’ managing partner wants to perform 
Panel (C) shows the merged table. Most ETL tools provide advanced support for data matching.
 Analytical database  5-5 
uously named tables, missing primary keys, and overlapping columns. 
and clear because they are part of the analytical database, which might have many different 
valued rule and make analysis more complex are composite columns and multi-valued columns.
Identify tables with a similar structure or tables that describe 
18.  (LO 6)  Discuss transforming models and how it differs from transforming columns. 
Table/Query:
Illustration 5.31 shows an intra-table validation rule for the Beans case. The values in 
In the Beans case the goal is to join the Employee and EmployeeDemographics tables. If both 
A table in your analytical database does not have a primary key.
2.  (LO 1)  Assume you are preparing an analytic database. You have downloaded raw data from the infor-
Remove Other Columns
5.4  Which Patterns Transform Columns?  5-21
columns. The Customer dimension table in Illustration 5.5 has ten columns but no measures. 
data are extracted from a relational database. However, a primary key will not be in place 
EmployeeDemographics tables contain employee information, so they should be merged into 
An entity’s data are spread across multiple tables, which 
Model transformation patterns deal with data issues across tables. 
Illustration 5.25 (A) shows the distinct values for the JobTitle column in the Employee table. 
 Scan Columns for Incorrect or Ambiguous Names
remove the column from the analytical database. If there is inconsistency in representing 
5.5  Which Patterns Transform Tables?  5-31
Database Transfer
These tables would have the same columns and similar data. Another option is to search 
Apply the necessary data preparation patterns to prepare an analytical database that makes it easy to 
(A) Customer Table:
A data model defines how different tables relate to each other. Analytical data models should 
columns within a table. Which of the following is the most appropriate response when she identifies 
star schema in Illustration 5.5 has dimension tables for the date the sale occurred, the product 
database that helps verify the 2025 depreciation expenses and the accumulated depreciation expenses. 
To identify similiarly structured tables, look for two or more tables with the same structure. 
5.4  Which Patterns Transform Columns?  5-23
ture). It can be gradually conducted at the column, table, and model 
Pattern 14 is similar to Pattern 10 in that it also defines acceptable values for a column. How-
Flat Tables 
STEP 6: As shown in Illustration 5.59, a new column is added to the Employee table 
it is the product table shown in panel (D) split vertically.
retail giants such as Amazon. The columns in fact tables are also mostly quantitative, and 
Dimension Tables 
the CertificationList column in the Employee table is a multi-valued column. Creating a new 
ical database. Illustration 5.16 (B) shows how to do this with Power Query. Select a column, 
nary can also be a helpful tool. For example, the Employee table contains information regard-
for tables that describe different characteristics of the same entity. In the Beans case, Employee 
cal database. Always consider alternatives, examine their strengths and weaknesses, and rank 
Combine Tables
ClData table and then select Rename and enter the new name: “ClientID.” Note that a col-
terns to the three files to create an analytical database that is consistent with the one shown here. 
uous descriptions should be a priority when developing an analytical database. Here are some 
b.	 split the column data into separate columns.
the analytical database is validated–that is, that all relationships have been defined.
that was sold, the customer, and the salesperson. Columns in dimension tables are variables 
